debugging Java and other JVM based
调试Java和其他基于JVM的
languages on IntelliJ IDEA is simple and
IntelliJ IDEA上的语言很简单并且
straightforward with console
控制台简单明了
applications this is simply a matter of
应用程序，这仅仅是一个问题
adding a new run configuration with your
与您的添加新的运行配置
main class any VM options and program
主类任何VM选项和程序
arguments that you'd like to use and
您要使用的参数和
then clicking debug in your run actions
然后在运行操作中单击调试
toolbar you can also kick off the
工具栏，您也可以启动
debugger from the main entry point for
从主要入口点开始的调试器
your application by clicking on or
通过单击或您的应用程序
inside that method and selecting debug
在该方法中并选择调试
which will launch your application
这将启动您的应用程序
attach an instance and wait for it to
附加一个实例并等待它
hit the first breakpoint and you can see
达到第一个断点，您可以看到
here that I've set this breakpoint up
在这里，我已经设置了这个断点
with a condition and this says whenever
有条件，这说每当
this variable inside my loop is 3 then
我循环内的这个变量是3
I'll stop the world you can also
我将停止世界，你也可以
configure additional options for
配置其他选项
conditional breakpoints by clicking more
通过单击更多有条件断点
and you can tell it to log any messages
你可以告诉它记录任何消息
to the console evaluate an expression
到控制台评估表达式
and remove the breakpoint once it's been
并删除断点后
hit we'll also be able to set up more
点击我们还可以设置更多
elaborate scenarios like chaining
复杂的场景，例如链接
conditional breakpoints so that they're
有条件的断点，以便
disabled until some other breakpoint is
禁用，直到其他断点
hit we can also specify certain filters
点击我们还可以指定某些过滤器
for this breakpoint so if we give it an
对于这个断点，所以如果我们给它一个
instance filter and the debugger will
实例过滤器和调试器将
only stop at instances of this class
仅在此类的实例处停止
with a matching instance ID if the
具有匹配的实例ID（如果
breakpoint is located inside an abstract
断点位于抽象内
class or default method then we can give
类或默认方法，那么我们可以给
it a class filter which will stop your
它是一个类过滤器，它将阻止您
programs runtime whenever it happens to
程序运行时
be inside concrete subclasses or sets of
在具体的子类或集合中
those inside your project and we can
您项目中的那些，我们可以
also exclude certain classes as well
也排除某些班级
finally the pass count filter will allow
最后通过计数过滤器将允许
you to tell the debugger to skip the
您告诉调试器跳过
first n times this breakpoint is hit
前n次击中此断点
this is helpful if you don't have any
如果您没有任何帮助，这将很有帮助
other landmarks inside your local scope
您当地范围内的其他地标
to feed into the conditional breakpoint
馈入条件断点
when you're debugging there are certain
当您调试时，
actions in the debug tool window that
调试工具窗口中的操作
you should be aware of such as the step
您应该注意诸如此类的步骤
actions you can step over a single line
您可以单行执行的操作
in your code
在你的代码中
by pressing step over or f8 you can step
通过按或键，您可以
into another stack frame by pressing
通过按入另一个堆栈框架
step into which will take you to the
一步将带您到
first call on that line and then step
首先在那条线上打电话，然后踩
back by pressing step out if you
如果您要退出，请按“退出”
navigate to another place inside your
导航到您内部的另一个地方
project or otherwise lose your place you
项目或以其他方式失去你的位置
can always return to the current
随时可以回到当前
execution point by pressing show
通过显示执行点
execution point finally if you'd like to
最后，如果您想执行点
run the debugger to a particular
将调试器运行到特定的
location inside your program but you
在程序中的位置，但您
don't necessarily want to set a
不一定要设置一个
breakpoint you can press run to cursor
可以按运行到光标的断点
which will pause the debugger wherever
它将在任何地方暂停调试器
your cursor has been placed when you'd
您将光标放在
like to resume you can press resume or
想继续，您可以按“继续”或
f9 and if the debugger doesn't respond
f9，如果调试器没有响应
for a long time say it's live lock to
很长一段时间说它是活锁
our spin locked somewhere but you don't
我们的自旋锁定在某个地方，但是你不
know where you can always go to the
知道你总是可以去哪里
threads console view and expand that
线程控制台视图并展开
here you'll be able to see the progress
在这里您可以看到进度
which threads are waiting you can pause
您可以暂停哪些线程
the program resume it and capture a
该程序将其恢复并捕获
thread dump to determine what may be the
线程转储以确定可能是
source of the congestion
拥塞的根源